[Mystic Nine]
[Adapted from the novel of Kennedy Xu]
[Episode 14]
[This story is purely fictional]
Master, Tu is dead.
You can take my Cui.
Cui?
Cui.
♪The river in Guangling flows like an emerald ribbon♪
♪The royal fleet sways to common woes♪
♪Don't ask from whence I came♪
You're in a good mood today.
You're singing a Xiangxi song.
We live to see another day.
And so I must sing joyfully.
Master Zhang,
to be honest with you,
I thought we were done for.
I performed a divination before I left,
and I got death.
You can die now.
Or people might say that your divination
never comes true.
They won't.
Because we ran into a Qiongqi.
My ancestors told me
that any divination involving a person
with a Qiongqi tattoo would never be accurate.
So you risked your life to come here.
What did you find?
Tell me.
Master Zhang,
that's not what I meant.
I meant...
Fine.
I'll tell you.
The ritual grass in the shrine
is in the style of Xiangxi.
In Xiangxi, the ritual grass is used in cave rituals.
Only the one who receives enlightenment in the cave
can take the ritual grass with them to preach.
Not only does the Otherworld Patriarch
has a tower in Changsha,
but he also has a cave in Xiangxi.
So Xiangxi it is, then.
Master Zhang,
I'm curious.
How did you find me?
I didn't leave
any traces behind on my journey.
Xiangu sent a messenger.
Master Zhang, can we speak?
Xiangu told me to come here.
She said Eighth Master was in grave danger,
and that you had to go to this place immediately.
Xiangu was so kind.
She sent Xiaomei to inform you.
That means she does like you.
She might not show
the same kindness to anyone else.
But Master Zhang,
the Huo Clan is a bandwagoner.
They have been working with Ding Qiansui closely lately.
They are waiting to see
who will win in the end.
The Mystic Nine, or Ding Qiansui.
Now that Xiangu has done me a favor,
she'll have a hard time answering to her clan.
While her clan is working with Ding Qiansui,
Xiangu herself still sides with the Mystic Nine.
She helped you because she cares.
The weather is great today.
Indeed.
Sing.
Master Zhang.
I only know two lines.
Sure, I'll continue.
♪Administer the medicine and help the sick♪
[Huo's Residence]
Xiaomei!
Put her down at once.
Why did you do that?
Because of you.
Why?
You told Zhang Qishan
Qi Tiezui's whereabouts.
She was punished on your behalf.
You don't know?
You have achieved what you wanted to achieve.
Isn't this
the outcome you seek?
Xiaomei knows nothing.
I merely gave her the order.
Just put her down.
At this point,
you should just worry about yourself.
No harming each other within the Mystic Nine.
I was just doing my job.
Foolish.
We nominated you as the head of the clan
because you are smart.
Do you really think
that you have the power to order us around?
Nian.
I once told you
that as long as you did Ding Qiansui's bidding,
anyone you cared about could become successful.
But you defied us.
This outcome
is the consequence of your action.
Do you know?
Ding Qiansui is already dead.
We have repaid our debt to him.
His life or death has nothing to do with us anymore.
Can't you see the bigger picture?
We are pawns.
We have a place to be.
Ding Qiansui became this powerful
because his mastermind wanted to use him
to eliminate the Mystic Nine.
Now that he's gone,
the mastermind wants to use us.
If we do their bidding,
we can easily become the head of Mystic Nine.
Ding Qiansui worked for the Japanese.
Are you planning to work with the Japanese?
I see it now.
Have you
already worked with the Japanese?
Don't you know
that they want to take over our nation?
And why does it matter to us?
Be it the Japanese or the Mystic Nine,
whoever can preserve our clan legacy
will be our friends.
Our legacy cannot fall.
Otherwise,
women like us
will suffer a horrible fate.
Surely, you are aware of that.
Girls!
This is your confession letter.
[Confession Letter]
Sign it
and receive your punishment.
I don't care.
We cannot work with the Japanese.
How delusional.
The moment we decided
to work with Ding Qiansui,
we already knew
there was no turning back.
Just sign it.
Madam.
Please.
Touch me if you dare.
You're asking for it.
Hit her!
Xiaomei.
Xiaomei!
Impossible.
If Hatoyama could do that,
why didn't he kill all of us already?
If he could kill across time and space,
I would be dead first.
But he chose to kill Ding Qiansui.
This doesn't make sense,
but they said
it wasn't a spell.
Ding Qiansui said that Yoshiyuki Hatoyama had been to Xiangxi.
Master.
We have news from Third Master.
The underground river
follows this route.
It leads to Xiangxi.
But it branches out
too much in Xiangxi. It's hard to judge where they went.
The discovery of the Otherworld Tower
is enough to earn him merits in Japan,
but he's still not content.
Master Zhang,
perhaps Xiangxi hides a bigger secret?
Eighth Master.
Ding Qiansui said that this was the secret
behind
Hatoyama's spells.
Have you seen this before?
See what?
It's so ugly.
Master Zhang.
What nonsense is this?
Urgh.
It's a golden pot.
It rotates when used.
Let's go now.
Ninth Master
will handle the origin of the pot.
But Xiangxi is huge.
How are we supposed to find them?
Yoshiyuki Hatoyama probably went to Xiangxi
to find
the cave in which the Otherworld Patriarch received enlightenment.
Master Zhang,
if we can solicit
the support from 82 Stockade,
we will definitely find the one
who saw the Otherworld Patriarch back then
and the location of the cave.
We'll depart immediately
to Xiangxi.
We already have troops stationed over there.
Tell them to contact 82 Stockade
and explain why we're there.
Noted.
But what should we say
if the Ministry of War inquires about our movement?
If we leave now,
Huo Wenhai can take over
Changsha.
Tell everyone
that Zhang Qishan
went to 82 Stockade to borrow soldiers
for Changsha's defense
and future battles.
It's a secret operation
and it won't be reported.
Yes.
Yoshiyuki Hatoyama
is a renowned scientist in Japan.
He planned carefully
to take
Laogou away from Changsha.
It seems like Laogou plays an important role
in the Japanese plan.
Fifth Master is a hooligan.
I don't see why the Japanese
think
he is so valuable.
Save Laogou.
Will you come or not?
Yes.
I have to be there.
Xiangu saved me.
Don't move.
Don't move!
Come out.
Mr. Wu,
speed up the progress now.
Zhang Qishan is trying his best to rescue you,
but it'll take him some time
to find this place.
Do you really expect him to save you?
So your falling out with him
was just a rumor then.
Guards.
Can you guess who they are?
Show us what you can do
or they will become its meal.
I was wondering
what a smart Japanese person like you
would do to torture me.
Disappointingly,
it's still the same old dirty trick.
Yes, the same old dirty trick
which works so well against the Chinese.
People wouldn't be suffering if Zhang Qishan
actually cared to save everyone.
Stop.
I'll tame it.
How long do you need?
Seven days.
Five days.
It takes time to tame it!
You have five days.
Fine. Five days.
Let them out now.
Now!
After five days,
I want to see the result.
Wait.
Then, I have to use my secret weapon.
Whatever you have in there is useless.
What do you need?
Taming a dog
is all about one thing.
Find their favourite food.
Even a wolf
will wag its tail when it smells
its favourite food.
Therefore,
find out what this beast
loves to eat.
What kind of food?
How would I know?
So,
go to the place where you captured it.
There might be a lot of leads there.
For example, hair, paw prints,
or even leftover bones.
Those will help me understand its instinct.
To tame it,
you start with its instinct.
Mr. Wu, you're trying to escape.
You think I can escape?
Bring him with us.
Yes!
What else do you need?
I need a whistle.
Give me a paper and a pen.
Give him what he wants.
[Otherworld Patriarch]
My child,
you are stubborn.
Come.
Let me show you your previous life.
I'll say it one more time.
[Silky Masterpiece]
I'm not part of the Wang Clan anymore.
I decide who I want to marry.
I joined this embroidery workshop because I wanted
nothing to do with hooligans like you.
Are you pushing your luck?
What are you doing?
- Hey! - Don't come near us.
You're in public now.
You can't hit us.
What is the meaning of this?
Is this how your clan does this?
Whoever marries you
will be miserable forever.
This is none of your business.
Move aside.
Hey!
- Madam! - Let me teach you a lesson.
[Lin Lanqing]
- Hey! - Stop.
Madam.
The Madam is here.
Madam, help me out.
Blacksmith Wang.
Instead of minding your business,
you came to bully the women of this workshop?
Lin Lanqing.
You're just a stupid spinster.
And now, you're housing a bunch of sleazy women
in your stupid embroidery workshop.
The whole Jiangning looks filthy
because of you.
Stupid embroidery workshop?
[Jiangning Women's Embroidery Workshop]
This plaque was given personally
by the Imperial Household Department.
Other than the Jiangning Weaving Bureau, no one has it.
[Jiangning Women's Embroidery Workshop]
I don't even have to report you
to the magistrate's office.
I can just report you to the Imperial Household Department.
Can you bear the consequences?
Madam, you are amazing.
When we go out,
everyone in Jiangning looks at us with respect.
That's right. That will show them what will happen to those
who cross us.
Yes.
Xiaoshu.
Today is an exception.
From now on,
do not quarrel with them.
I didn't do it. They started...
Lanqing.
Mr. Magistrate.
At ease.
You're dismissed.
Mr. Magistrate.
How can I help you?
The higher-up
placed an emergency order.
500 bolts per month,
for a total amount of 3,000 bolts.
I...
That's nearly 30% of the Weaving Bureau's annual output.
You're not the only one who received the order.
From Hangzhou all the way to Suzhou,
every workshop has to produce hundreds of bolts now.
Mr. Magistrate,
our workshop only has around 100 people, and we sew by hand.
We won't reach this number even if we sew till we die.
The higher you are, the greater you fall.
Are you trying to defy the imperial decree?
You'll lose your reputation,
your plaque,
and even your family members.
What are you doing?
Am I getting killed?
Be nice.
Let go of me!
Let go!
Madam, we didn't mean to run away.
That's right, Madam.
Our fingers are cut.
Our eyes are blurry.
We are just a burden to the workshop.
Please spare us.
If all of you run away,
the rest
will die.
But if we continue working like this,
we'll die from exhaustion too, Madam.
Please spare us.
- Madam. - Madam.
Mercy.
Madam.
I beg you, Madam.
Take them away.
Don't do this, Madam.
- Madam. - Madam.
Madam!
Don't do this.
Madam.
You said women in this workshop should not hurt each other.
Why did you break the promise?
I
had no choice.
You earned this plaque
with your needle and thread.
In the past, we enjoyed the glory and the fame.
You said it'd protect us.
But I don't see any protection now,
only suffering.
Women like us
fight an uphill battle
to survive in this world.
In this workshop, we can feel safe.
We won't be bullied.
And we owe it to our needlework.
If the workshop falls,
and the plaque is gone,
we will be forced
to marry men
or sold as slaves.
What we can do now
is to embroider obediently
to keep our workshop alive.
There is no other way.
To be enslaved by others
or to be enslaved here,
what difference does it make?
[Huo Clan Salt Mine]
Xiaomei.
Miss Huo.
Have I carried out the task you gave me?
Yes, you did so well.
Don't worry.
I'll bring you out.
You're awake?
Is this the salt mine?
You can't tell?
Huo Clan salt mine.
If you're awake, start working now.
She's seriously injured.
Can you find a doctor to treat her?
Are you bossing me around?
Do you think you're still the head of the clan?
You want a doctor?
Listen.
Your confession letter is still here in the mine.
You have been disowned by the Huo Clan.
You're as good as dead.
This is your afterlife.
From now on, you'll listen to us.
Play nice.
Don't move. Or I'll cut her.
- Hurry up. - Be quick.
Quick.
- Work now. - Don't be lazy.
Work fast.
Let's go.
Lock the gate.
There are only black plague patients inside. She'll die soon.
Xiaomei.
Xiaomei!
Look. It's so beautiful.
So pretty.
Xiaozhu obeys the dog whistle.
It can command every dog in my clan.
It will hide by your side every day,
and will appear when you need it.
[Memorial Tablet of Huo Clan's Great Matron]
[Memorial Tablet of Huo Clan's Founding Matron]
My sisters,
we have to appoint a new head today.
Take a good look.
Pick an obedient girl.
All of you, leave now.
Xiaomei.
I brought you back.
How did you get out?
Guards!
Touch me if you dare.
Everyone in the salt mine is dead.
If you want to join them,
feel free.
And my three honorable aunts,
any tricks you have left?
I'm waiting.
May I know what the important occasion is?
I see the elders of the Huo Sisters Guild
have gathered here with everyone else.
Today,
we will appoint a new head of the clan
because the previous head
is dead.
Is this a joke, my aunt?
Aren't I alive?
When I say you're dead,
you are dead.
Bring them out.
They are
your loyal sisters.
They have been helping you.
They even got on their knees to beg me
when I sent you to the salt mine.
They asked me to spare you.
Surely, you don't want
to see them dead here.
And where is your mother's memorial tablet?
Don't you want to find out?
So you have been plotting against me
the moment I became the head of the clan.
The kindness you showed when I was little
was all fake.
Our ancestral teaching is right.
Never trust anyone.
Never fall in love.
Nian,
you have finally
understood this.
But you have to make a choice now.
Save them
or save yourself.
What fictitious crime do you want me to carry this time?
Anything.
Maybe you're brokenhearted because your lover, Wu Laogou,
is dead,
so you want to follow his footsteps.
Nian.
Drink it.
Your mother's memorial tablet will be kept safely,
and your loyal sisters can live.
No!
Time is running out.
We are old now.
Make your decision now.
- No! - No!
Xiangu, I love you the most here.
Two days ago, I saw them burning letters in the backyard.
One of them concerns your mother.
[Yuhua has fallen in Northwest China]
And I hid it.
Then, they captured us.
From now on,
you are the head of the clan.
Following our ancestral rules,
your mother has to leave the clan.
For you, your mother
went to Northwestern China alone.
It's a harsh place with no means of communication.
So, she told me to tell you
that from now on,
prioritize our clan legacy over your own life.
Manage our clan well.
Nian.
Aunt.
My mother is...
Your mother
was killed
[Memorial Tablet of Huo Yuhua]
by the vagrants in Northwestern China.
So you asked
Ding Qiansui to kill my mother.
- No. - That's not true.
I've always been the kindest to you.
It was her.
It was her. It has nothing to do with me.
She did it.
We didn't do it.
It wasn't us.
First Aunt.
From now on,
I'll take over the Huo Clan.
I'll remove our old scars
one by one.
I'll find another way
to keep this clan alive.
But this future
is not for you to see.
♪The past fades like smoke♪
♪A choice is made in silence♪
♪In this labyrinthine puzzle♪
♪Who can reach the shore?♪
♪Just an ordinary farewell♪
♪The sun seems to shine bright over our heads♪
♪But this could be our last trip together♪
♪The spring breeze continues outside♪
♪Who was it who left in such haste?♪
♪Caught in the game, the raging waves fall silent♪
♪Who believes in fate?♪
♪For my home and my country, the years pass like a dream♪
♪When the song ends, who will still be waiting?♪
♪With a nod, we bid farewell and set out again♪
♪Take care♪
♪We once raced♪
♪For the dawn♪
♪Ever-lasting bond, a satisfying vindication♪
♪In the web of fate♪
♪No one can escape♪
♪Life and death cut like a blade♪
♪We too were young once♪
♪Fortunate to brave the raging waves together♪
♪Keep the ember lit♪
♪To illuminate the journey ahead♪
♪The spring breeze continues outside♪
♪Who was it who left in such haste?♪
♪Caught in the game, the raging waves fall silent♪
♪Who believes in fate?♪
♪For my home and my country, the years pass like a dream♪
♪When the song ends, who will still be waiting?♪
♪With a nod, we bid farewell and set out again♪
♪Please, do take care of yourself♪